[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[RAIN PATTERING]
NEWS ANCHOR: Breaking news from California,
at the Metropolitan Courthouse in downtown Los Angeles.
A now familiar scene,
an officer accused
of the shooting
of an unarmed
African-American male
in the Southwest Division
last August has been
found not guilty.
The officer involved
fatally shot
a 19-year-old victim...
Hey, Pops.
...after a chase
over a suspected drug deal.
The officer claimed he thought
the victim was reaching
for a gun in his car...
Can I get a coffee?
It's not working, man.
...which turned out
to be his wallet.
What?
Prosecutors accused
the officers of entering
into a conspiracy...
Then let me get
a medium Coke.
...with other officers
to plant misleading evidence
at the scene,
including a weapon.
All across the city
and the nation,
including Swinton,
spontaneous protests
have erupted to decry
the verdict,
as well as to protest
police violence.
At the courthouse,
activists gathered outside
and marched through downtown.
Various peaceful protests
escalated, as objects
were thrown at City Hall,
as well as several
police vehicles.
At least 14 people
were arrested.
Three officers have been
treated for wounds,
including one...
POPS: You're not welcome
here today, Kevin.
Not today, man.
KEVIN: Was she amazing?
Oh, that's my baby.
That's my princess.
Was it the blue dress?
[GASPS] I know.
I know. I know.
I wish I could be there, too.
There's a lot going on,
all right? You know.
I'm doing this for us.
It'll all be over soon enough.
I won't miss anything else.
Okay, I love you,
too, baby.
Hey, baby. I gotta go.
All right? Bye.
[SIREN WAILS]
Dispatch, this is
18-Lincoln-4. Over.
DISPATCHER:
18-Lincoln-4, go ahead.
Central, show me
with a car pull-over
at East 11th
and South Dakota.
I have a green Chevy van
with left tail light out.
No tags.
DISPATCHER:
10-4, 18-Lincoln-4.
[BRAKES SCREECHING]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[CAMERA BEEPS]
KEVIN: Ma'am, can you roll
your window down, please?
[CONTINUES KNOCKING]
Ma'am, roll your
window down now.
[LOUDLY] Ma'am,
place your hands
on the steering wheel.
Right now!
Step out of the van!
Exit the vehicle!
Get out of your vehicle now!
Turn around! Turn around!
Get your hands on the vehicle.
Put your hands in the air now.
Put your hands
on the vehicle now!
Do you understand
what I'm saying to you?
Turn around now!
Don't make me
hurt you, please.
Are you on...
Get on the ground.
What is wrong...
[KEVIN SCREAMING]
[MELANCHOLY MUSIC PLAYING]
MAN: Some of this
may sound redundant.
I appreciate your patience
as we hammer through
these questions again, Renee.
Please bear with me
as the standard review questions are cursory.
I just wanna dig in
one more time
to what we've been
talking about over the week.
Okay? Have you had any
trouble sleeping?
RENEE: No.
MAN: Any trouble
relating to people?
RENEE: No.
MAN: Have you had
violent impulses?
RENEE: As we talked about,
it was
a complicated situation.
Renee, you struck
a civilian.
People can say
whatever they want
about what happened.
The administration
and the public
saw your body cam
footage, Renee.
They saw how you
handled that.
Look, I gotta be
on point.
I have to walk up
to strangers.
Some of them are hostile.
Can you handle
that stress?
[SIGHS]
Have you moved on
from your son's death?
I need to work.
I really need to work.
Okay.
I'm going to recommend you
return to active duty
on nights again, okay?
Yes. Thank you, sir.
Appreciate it.
You can start the next shift.
Watch commander will pair you.
[SIREN BLARING]
KESPER: We had
an alley dump last night.
Female, Latina, 20s.
No ID, no suspects
at this time.
So be on the lookout.
Check with your CIs.
See if you can get anything.
Also, with the acquittal
of our brother officers
yesterday,
Mr. and Mrs. Public
are gonna be
all out of sorts,
so be gracious. Courteous.
Don't start shit.
Good to see you.
KESPER: Stay poised.
Also, let's welcome back
Officer Lomito.
[APPLAUSE]
She is officially
back in the badge.
And according to my notes,
she's buying everybody
a beer after watch.
[ALL CHATTERING
AND APPLAUDING]
Okay, that's it. Let's go
do work. Stay safe.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
RENEE: Sarge, you put me
with a rookie. Really?
I get it. Help me out.
[SIGHS]
Hey, come here.
Welcome back, lady.
Thanks, Sarge.
KESPER:
Don't slap anyone today.
OFFICER 1: All right.
Here you go.[CAMERA BEEPS]
[CAMERA BEEPS]
OFFICER 2: Here you go.
It might be crazy
out there tonight.
Yes.
I didn't know that
you scuba dived.
KEVIN: I don't,
but I will.[LAUGHS]
Just been itching
to get back on the job.
Yeah.
How's everything? Okay.
It's good.
What up?
Danny Holledge?
Yeah. Officer Lomito?
Yeah. We're partnering
together.
Danny, this is Penda, Ganning,
Birke and Roberts.
Oh, yeah. We know
this fuck-face.
Ganning was his first CO.
Tried his best to break him.
Holledge, you got yourself
a good babysitter.
[DANNY CHUCKLES]
You got yourself squared?
Yep.
All right, y'all be safe.
PENDA: You be safe, Renee.
Thanks, guys.
Hey, Danny.
Public's got no love
for us right now.
Your head down,
your eyes open.
Stay close to Renee.
All right. Got it.
Head down, eyes open.
But not too close.
[CHUCKLES]
Can I go?
Yeah.
If you're looking to make
a little extra cash, Danny,
I could use somebody
to mow my lawn on Sunday.
Fuck you.
Fuck you, guys.
You're welcome.
BIRKE: Pink is your color.
PENDA: Can't be too careful.
BIRKE: I mean, she punched
somebody in the face.
ROBERTS:
Watch that right hook.
[HIP-HOP SONG PLAYING]
DANNY: You know,
those guys back there,
they're just, you know,
fucking around.
They do really respect me.
They don't actually...
You know, I'm not a baby,
I've been doing this
for a good minute.
RENEE: Hmm...
[DISPATCHER SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY ON RADIO]
Should we put on some music,
or are we just gonna
sit here in total silence?
Hey, looks
like a kid.Yeah.
[HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYING
IN DISTANCE]
[CAMERAS BEEPING]
[DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE]
What's up, little guy?
Hey. Hi there.
It's okay, sweetie.
DANNY:
What you doing out here?
Just wanna
make sure you're okay.
Calm down. It's okay.
[MAN SHOUTING]
Hey. Take it easy.
We're good, we're good.
Hey. Get away from him.
WOMAN 2:
Come on, come inside.
Sorry, ma'am. Just trying to
make sure he's okay.
Mind your own damn business.
Come on, baby.
DANNY: You got yourself
a little boy in the middle
of the...
Hey, back up, back up.
Back up, back up. Back up now.
MAN: What's happening here?
RENEE: Everything's all right.
Everything's all right.
Calm down. Just trying to
make sure the kid's all right.
He was in the street.
Go back to your homes, okay?
[ALL CLAMORING]
Hey.
Just relax.
Everything's good.
Come on.
[PEOPLE CLAMORING]
The police, man
Useless, man.
RENEE: Go back to your homes.
Everything is okay.
Have a good night.
[PEOPLE CLAMORING]
[SIGHS]
That was good,
how you handled that, though.
RENEE: Thanks.
DISPATCHER: Dispatch to
18-Adam-7, come in. Over.Go for 18-Adam-7.
18-Adam-7, code two,
East 11th and South Dakota,
18-Lincoln-4.
Failure to respond.
We're code six.
That's Ganning.
Yeah.
Dispatch, 18-Adam-7
en route to location.
DISPATCHER: 18-Adam-7,
proceed with caution.
RENEE: 18-Adam-7, responding. ETA, three minutes.
[SIREN BLARING]
He's probably
just fucking around.
No, it's not like him.
What the hell happened
to the street lights?
Dispatch, this is 18-Adam-7.
Spotted 18-Lincoln-4
on East 11th and South Dakota.
The cruiser is down.
DISPATCHER:
10-4, 18-Adam-7.
Rolling backup.
18-Adam-9...
Shit.
Danny.
Oh, shit.
Fucking teeth?
Not working.
Fucking thing is shot.
Grab the big light,
check the north side.
Send me more units.
Still trying to locate
18-Lincoln-4. Over.
DISPATCHER:
Copy, 18-Adam-7.
KEVIN: Hey.
Hey. Hey.
Holledge.
KEVIN: Hands on
the steering wheel.
Put your hands
on the steering wheel.
Get out
of the vehicle now.
Ma'am, get out
of your vehicle now.
Green van, no plates.
[INDISTINCT SCREECH]
[GLASS BREAKING]
[TYPING]
Oh, my God. Kevin.
[SCREAMING]
Danny.
DANNY: You got something?
RENEE: There's gotta be
a way in here.
What the hell? Shit.
[GASPS]
[RETCHING]
[MACHINE WHIRRING]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
So what do we got?
Green Chevy van.
No plates.
Ganning pulled
the vehicle over.
Pulls his weapon on
a female, black, 30s.
Whoa, whoa,
the driver?
RENEE: I'm not sure.
The footage cut out.
The footage
doesn't exist, Renee.
IT said that
the card got fried
when Ganning's car
got hit.
I saw that footage, sir.
So who hit his car?
The green van?
Ganning's body cam
got fried, too. It's blank.
Kesper, so these two
were the primary unit
that took the call?
We saw a black female, 30s.
So one woman did all this?
Is that why you screwed
around with the dash cam?
You know protocol.
It's evidence, Officer.
By touching it,
you're interfering
with the crime scene.
Sarge...
Okay, okay.
I'll meet you back there.
HAYES:
If you wanna help Ganning,
write up what you saw
while it's still fresh
in your mind.
DANNY:
This is fucking bullshit.
RENEE: Come on, man.
Let's go. Let's get a drink.
DANNY: Thank you, hon.
Bourbon, rocks.
Thanks, man.
What you drinking?
Club soda.
Shit. Ganning was
my first partner.
I can't fucking believe
that he's dead. It's crazy.
I mean, who the fuck
would do
something like that
to him? It's bullshit.
And it doesn't make
any sense.
No, it doesn't make
Doesn't give you
any faith in humanity.
And that fucking detective
telling us that
we can go home?
Yeah, I know. How could
I tell her what I saw?
The whole department's
just waiting for me
to fuck up again.
Why?
'Cause I hit a guy.
Yeah, I saw
that video, too.
Shit.
Everybody's seen
that video.Yeah.
That guy, he just
wouldn't shut up.
He just kept talking
and talking.
Just being disrespectful,
you know?
What was he saying?
He said some shit like,
"You black bitch."
And I blacked out.
Lost it.
Body cam footage
was all they needed
to take me off the street
for eight months.
I mean, listen,
I'm not unstable.
I was going through
a lot. I lost my son.
Shit.
He drowned
in our neighbor's pool.
I'm sorry about that.
[DOOR CLOSES]
GARY: Hey, my queen.
RENEE: Hey.
You're home early.
[SIGHS]
What happened? What?
Ganning.
He was killed.
Oh, my God.
[SIGHS]
I'm so sorry.
Are you okay?
No.
I feel almost
out of touch with reality.
I can't even explain
what I saw.
Something terrible happened,
and I have to find out why.
Wait. It's your
first day back.
Can't they put
someone else on it?
This man was
like my brother.
You're too close to Ganning,
or Christopher.
It's all just too much.
I can't have another person
close to me die,
without trying
to do something.
I felt so helpless
with Christopher.
I still feel helpless.
I've got to
do something.Hey.
Don't worry.
You're not alone.
CHRISTOPHER: Mom!
Mom!
KEVIN: Ma'am! Ma'am! Ma'am!
Place your hands on the wheel. Step out of the van!
Will you roll
your window down?
Ma'am, get out
of the vehicle now!
[SCREAMING]
Dispatch, this is
18-Adam-7.
Need a DMV check on
a Taneesha Branz. Age, 34.
DISPATCHER: Copy that.
That woman on
Ganning's dash cam,
I might know who she is.
This was on her scrubs.
DANNY: What is it?
It's Swinton Hospital.
I remember it when
I had my son there.
Checked the staff website.
She hasn't worked there
in six months.
DISPATCHER:
18-Adam-7, Taneesha Branz,
1733 North Dorgenois.
No wants. No warrants.
RENEE: Copy that.
Lomito.
No, leave it off for now.
It's my business.
[DOGS BARKING IN DISTANCE]
RENEE: For Taneesha Branz.
This was sent
like a month ago.
[MUFFLED RUMBLING]
RENEE: Taneesha Branz?
There's gotta be
another way in.
Let's try the side.
[MUFFLED RUMBLING]
DANNY: You see anything?
RENEE:
Just a bunch of clothes.
[DOORKNOB RATTLES]
[WHISPERS]
Lomito?
[DOOR CREAKS]
RENEE: It's open.
Come on.
Oh, shit.
[SWITCH CLICKING]
There's nothing.
RENEE: Look for any evidence
linking her
to Ganning's murder.
DANNY: Okay.
This must be her son.
[DOORKNOB RATTLES]
RENEE: What the hell?
[DOOR CREAKING]
[CREAKING]
RENEE: You hear that?
DANNY: We need to
get out of here, Renee.
[MUFFLED THUD]
RENEE:
Someone's in here.
[GRUNTS]
Fuck!
All right, Lomito,
I'm out of here. Fuck this.
[FLOORBOARD CREAKING]
Holledge, is that you
running around upstairs?
DANNY: [OVER RADIO]
I'm outside.
There's nobody in there. I don't see anybody in there.
Police officer.
Who's there?
[YELLS]
RENEE: See anyone?
DANNY: No,
I didn't see anybody.
I just had like 1000
fucking cockroaches
fly at me.
I'm feeling like...
What?
Crazy.
[DANNY STAMMERS]
I don't know
how I feel about this.
You know,
you checking out
your own leads.
I don't know really if I can
do this. It's like...
I think it's kind of
freaking me out.
RENEE: You gotta
trust me. Okay?
Okay,
I trust you.
Okay?
Let's go.
[DANNY SIGHS]
Fucking roaches, man.
I'd rather get shot at.
[CAR ENGINE STOPS]
[TYPING]
MAN 1: Yeah, I want
my fucking money.
I want my fucking money.
I'm telling you,
I want my money.
You stupid ass.
How you gonna steal
a stick-shift when
you can't drive?
You wanna ride people.
You can't do that, dude.
MAN 2:
Thinking for everybody.
MAN 1: I'm not playing
with him.
MAN 2: Oh, man.
He stupid, bro.
MAN 1: And he's
running around here,
with jewelry
all on his neck.
MAN 2: Crazy, bro.
[MUSIC PLAYING ON SPEAKERS]
[BELL JINGLES]
Thank you.
WOMAN: Thanks.
[BELL JINGLES]
MAN 2: Mr. Never-have.
I got you.
What's up, brother? You got
a charger? My phone dead.
Don't have any.
[MAN 1 LAUGHS]
MAN 2: You didn't even ask me
what kind of phone I got.
Hey, buddy.
Come on, man.
It's a neighborhood store.
Come on.
[MAN 2 CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY]
I don't have
a charger, sir.
USB.
I don't have any.
MAN 2: How you doing?
[LAUGHS]
MAN 2: Go look
in the back, man.
No. Hey, put that back.
MAN 2: Man, what you gonna do?
CASHIER: Put the beer back.
Hey.
Hey, woman.
CASHIER: Buddy,
come on, man. Come on.
Why you hiding?
CASHIER: Don't do this.
MAN 2: Charger.
CASHIER:
I don't have a charger.MAN 2: Look in the back.
You ain't gonna tell me?
You scared of me?
Huh?
[LAUGHS]
Yo. Leave her alone.
Shut the fuck up.
[SHOUTS IN HINDI]
[IN ENGLISH] Leave her alone!
MAN 1: I said,
shut the fuck up!
Get the fuck out, man.
Get the fuck out of my store.
MAN 1: Shut up.
We're not going nowhere, bro.
CASHIER: You are. Let's see.
We're not going
no-motherfucking-where.
I'm gonna report your
motherfucking ass.
Hey. I'm right here.
Say it. Say you're scared.
ROBERTS: Come on now.
BIRKE: What does having...
Hey. Green van. No plates.
Reported at Ganning's
pull-over, right?
BIRKE: Goddamn right.
Hey, Dispatch, this is
18-Indie-5 checking 1154.
Green van, no plates,
in the 1300 block of Ripley.
Possible vehicle involved
in Ganning's homicide.
Requesting backup. Over.
DISPATCHER: 10-4, 18-Indie-5.
Backup responding. Proceed with extreme caution.
DISPATCHER:
18-Adam-7, code two.
1300 block of Ripley.
18-Adam-5, sighting of
a green van. No plates.
Requesting backup.
[SIREN BLARING]
Hey.
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
Who owns the van?
CASHIER:
They're stealing things, man.
We're not stealing nothing.
This man lying, bro.
CASHIER: He's stealing.
You driving the van
out front?No, sir.
We ain't drive no van.
Down on your knees.
Hands above your head.
Fuck this.
Drop the phone and get
down on your knees.
Dude, I just told you,
we're not driving that shit.
Do you have
any weapons on you?
This is fucked up.
Keep filming, bro.
I don't got nothing on me.
I don't got
shit on me, sir.Shut up!
[GROANS]
MAN 1: Let us out!
Hey, Birke! Birke!
Can you hear me?
[COUGHING]
Let me and my boy out of here.
Birke, say something.
What the fuck, bro?
Fuck that, man.
I ain't going back.
Birke! Birke!
[CHOKING]
Let us out.
Let her go, or I'll
light your ass up!
Think I'm playing?
Birke, talk to me.
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
[MAN 1 GROANING]
[GUNSHOTS]
[MAN 2 GROAN]
[CASHIER GROANS]
Birke.
[PANTING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[CHOKING]
[GRUNTING]
[PANTING]
[WHIMPERING]
[GROANING]
[SCREAMS]
[SCREAMING]
DANNY: [OVER RADIO]
Dispatch, this is 18-Adam-7
arriving for backup,
1300 block of Ripley.
Did 18-Indie-5
report back? Over.
DISPATCHER:
18-Indie-5 went code six
a few minutes ago.
Roger that. Scanning
the area. Over.
[CAMERA BEEPS]
RENEE: Clear.
Clear.
Officer down.
Shit. She's dead.
Dispatch, it's 18-Adam-7.
We got an officer down.
Send an EMT now.
DISPATCHER:
18-Adam-7, dispatching
ambulance...
[CRACKLING]
[LABORED BREATHING]
[WHISPERS] Shit.
RENEE: Shit.
Second officer down.
Dispatch,
this is 18-Adam-7.
Correction. We've got
two officers down, okay?
Send an ambulance
immediately!
DISPATCHER:
Copy, 18-Adam-7.
Clear.
[DOOR OPENS]
[STATIC HISSING]
[STATIC STOPS]
RENEE: There you are.
MAN 2: ...on me, sir.
MAN 1: Fuck!
[GUNSHOTS]
[INDISTINCT SCREAM]
[SIRENS APPROACHING]
HAYES: So, apparently,
the security cameras
in this place are
completely cosmetic,
because there's nothing
on the cards. They're blank.
I'd put out an APB
on a black woman, mid 30s.
Someone you saw
on the scene?
RENEE: I'm thinking
it's the same woman
from Ganning's dash cam.
Did you see a woman here?
Um...
No.
Okay, listen. This is
what we've got so far.
We ran the VIN number
on the van.
It's the property
of the pastor of
a church on Gaskell.
We questioned him
after Ganning's murder,
and he said that his van
completely disappeared.
We figure that the perps
that were in there got it,
Ganning tried to bust them,
and they killed him.
It appears that Roberts
and Birke found these guys.
Did they say
how they were killed?
Uh, no. We're still
working on it.
We'll take it
from here.
Renee.
They're gonna try to pin
Ganning's murder on these two.
That's good, right?
Yeah, but they
weren't the ones
driving the van
when he pulled it over.
Taneesha Branz was.
What are you talking about?
Come on.
[INDISTINCT POLICE RADIO
CHATTER]
What are you doing?
Did you take that?
Is that evidence?
What are they
gonna say when you...
What the fuck
are they gonna say
when they find that
you're stealing evidence?
You're the only one
that knows.No, I'm not doing this.
Relax.
No, Renee.
All right? You're
on your own trip.
Fuck you.
No, fuck you.
I think you're a mother
who lost her kid,
and you've become obsessed
with some woman who lost hers.
And now you're saying
a bunch of crazy shit.
All this stuff
with this lady.
They found their guys.
You need to fucking let it go.
What the fuck
do you mean, "let it go"?
Okay? Just leave it alone.
[SIGHS]
[SOFT JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING]
Oh, hey, Renee.
How are you doing?
I've been better.
I hear that.
What can I do for you?
You processed a couple
of bodies that came in.
Couple of special ones.
Yeah, I know
what you're talking about.
Are you wanting
to see them?
I can't do it.
It's not protocol.
I'll get in trouble.
You can give me those
brown eyes all you want,
but I'm telling you,
I just can't do it.
Weren't you the one
that found them?Yeah.
If I get in trouble,
I'm coming after you.
Quite a mess.
Well, here he is.
You can see
how he's mangled.
right around there,
just teeth coming through
a cheek there, I think.
I don't know.
But his associate
over here,
that's a different story
altogether.
Get a load of this shit.
I get scalps coming in
in all kinds of conditions,
but I've never had
anything come in
looking like this.
Did they put in
what the official cause was?
There's no official cause.
They're gonna fly
a medical examiner in
from Chicago
to look at these two guys,
because everybody's pretty
fucked up about what happened.
Mind if I get
a moment alone?
Uh...
Renee, this is my job,
and I love it for what it is.
Look, I understand.
I'm gonna give you
five minutes.
But please don't
fuck anything up.
Don't take anything.
[SIGHS]
And cut the lights off
when you leave.
Cool.
Hurry up.
[ZIPPING]
[GUNSHOTS]
MAN 1: You think it's a game?
You think
I won't kill her, huh?
Let us out. Let me
and my boy out of here.
You think it's a game?
You think
I won't kill her, huh?
Let us out. Let me
and my boy out of here.
[DISTORTED]
Let me and my boy out of here. You think it's a game?
You think
I won't kill her, huh?
Let us out.
[GUNSHOTS]
[WOMAN GASPS]
[DISTORTED]
You think
I won't kill her, huh?
Let us out.
GARY: Babe?
[GASPS]
You coming up to bed?
Yeah. I'll be up
in a minute.
All right.
RENEE: What the...
[BEEPING]
[CLICKS]
[SAFE BEEPS]
CHRISTOPHER: No, you're
the coolest mom ever.
I just really want
you to be safe, you know?
You're always out there, and, you know, you have a gun,
and people might hurt you. I don't want them to hurt you.
Mom, I just wanna protect you, no matter what.
I just wanna protect you,
but I can't.
Nor can Dad.
No one can. No one can.
KESPER: In this job,
what matters is what
we do and how we do it.
We're never gonna
get the respect we deserve,
because nobody
outside this room knows
how hard this job is.
Respect doesn't come
from out there.
It comes from in here.
This week, we lost
two more of our own.
Officer Gabe Roberts
and Maria Birke.
I know some of you
may despair,
but let me remind you
that when we're attacked,
we stand tall.
We stand together.
And we are strong.
Just a reminder that
this weekend we have
the wake for Gabe and Maria,
so I know
I'll see you all there.
Okay, that's it.
Let's go. Be safe.
KESPER: I'm sorry.
I know you've been
going through a lot.
I got a lot of respect
for you.
Mm-hmm.
I'm glad you're back.
These times, we need
all of us together.
You know, we're like a family.
Whenever you need
an ear, I'm here. Okay?
[INAUDIBLE CONVERSATION]
Excuse me.
Sure.
RENEE: Hey, Penda.
Hey, Renee.
It's sad, huh?
Yeah. Everything all right?
Remember the killing of a kid
named DeMarco Branz?
Taneesha Branz
was his mother's name.
That was a kid
in an empty lot.
Looked like
a drive-by gang thing.
We found him bled out.
Pretty obvious
what happened.Right.
Thank you.
Danny.
Renee.
Renee. You have
the best name, Renee.
Did you know that
your name, Renee,
is Kermit the Frog
in Spanish?
So, they don't even have
a Kermit.
They just have
a Renee the Frog.
Ganning has a good name, too.
Ganning, Roberts, Birke.
RENEE: Danny.
Hey, hey, hey.
I wasn't ready for this.
I wasn't ready
for any of this shit.
I thought that
I was ready, but I wasn't.
There's a lot going on
right now. Just...
What's going on
with you?
What happened
to the club soda?
No more alcohol.
Okay.
Okay?
MAN 1: Let me and
my boy out of here.
You think it's a game?
[CELL PHONE VIBRATING]
You think
I won't kill her, huh?
Let us out.
[DISTORTED]
Let me and my boy out of here.
You think it's a game?
You think
I won't kill her, huh?
Let us out.
[KNOCKING AT DOOR]
Let me and my boy out of here.
You think it's a game?
You think
I won't kill her, huh?
Let us out.
[KNOCKING CONTINUES]
[SCREECHING]
GARY: You okay, baby?
[SIGHS]
RENEE:
Look, I'm sorry, Gary.
I don't wanna stress you out
with everything
that's happening to me.
[SIGHS]
Let's just take care
of us right now.
Go someplace peaceful,
a vacation or something.
You know?
Share the weight
with me, please.
I feel like there's
a different reality
that only I can see.
There's only one reality.
We share it.
For all we know it,
could be stress.
[SIGHS]
It's not stress.
Yeah, after what
we went through,
nobody expects us to be
rational through this.
And I wanna help.
You can't help.
I gotta figure
this out on my own.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[INDISTINCT POLICE RADIO
CHATTER]
DANNY: People are
talking about you.
They think you're losing it.
And I'm scared for you.
Everybody keeps saying,
you know,
"She's chasing her own leads.
She's playing detective."
Look, all these things
that keep happening,
they mean something.
I'm just trying
to do the right thing.
So am I. All right?
Lomito, I'm just trying
to get through training,
and keep my head down,
and not fuck anything up.
And I'm trying to help you
save your job
because I care about you.
Okay?
Okay.
Danny.
Yeah.
Look, I need you.
In or out?
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Pierce, I need info.
I need an address
from a detective's report
that was filed from
Ganning's case.
A church Hayes mentioned.
Can you help me out?
The lou asked me
to do a follow-up.
Just a couple
of questions.
Okay.
Ask me 'cause
I know everything.
Thomas Cozzalio Jackson.
Over on East Adams.
Officer,
how can I help you?
You told our detectives
that a green van
disappeared
off your property.
It wasn't stolen, was it?
You lent it
to Taneesha Branz.
If you impede
an investigation,
that's obstruction
of justice.
Come to the back,
and we can speak properly.
We've got about
20 kids in the program.
This is the activity room.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
And this is the room
where Taneesha used to take
her son, DeMarco.
DeMarco was one
of the smartest kids
we'd ever worked with.
Intense.
Devoted to his mom,
who was maybe a little
too protective of him.
They were close.
Look at this.
DeMarco couldn't hear.
But he was a resourceful child
who found ways to communicate.
Fourteen years old,
but there wasn't a day
he wasn't out
in this city somewhere,
doing volunteer work
or community service.
That's the kind of boy
that he was.
Then he gets killed
by senseless violence.
What do you think
that kind of loss
does to a mother?
Where's Taneesha?
She needs to get
off the street
before somebody else dies.
And you'll help her?
I'll do what I can.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
RENEE: Taneesha?
[GUN COCKS]
[DEVICE BEEPING]
[INDISTINCT POLICE RADIO
CHATTER]
[SIGHS]
[LINE RINGING]
KESPER: [ON RECORDING]
This is Kesper.
Leave a message.
[BEEPS]
Sarge, I need your help.
This is Renee. Hit me back.
Hey, Renee. Hi.
RENEE: Holledge.
Listen to me. I need
to see you right now.
Why?
RENEE: Not over the phone.
I tracked down Taneesha.
Penda may be involved
in some bad shit.
Holledge.
Okay. Okay.
Give me an hour.
All right.
Thanks, Danny.
Danny!
Danny.
[WATER RUNNING]
[MAN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY ON TV]
[CLOSES FAUCET]
RENEE: Oh, no, no, no.
Fuck.
[MELANCHOLY MUSIC PLAYING]
[SIGHS]
DANNY: It's the police!
It's the police!
KEVIN: Suspect spotted.
Let's go.
DANNY: It's the police!
KEVIN: Yeah, that's him.
He fits the description.
DANNY: Hey, stop!
Stop where you are!
Right now!
KEVIN: Stop!
ROBERTS: Hey!
Hey, turn around!
PENDA: Suspect is resisting.
KEVIN: Get on your knees now!
DANNY: On your knees!
KEVIN: On your knees!
[GUNSHOT]
[MAN GROANS]
DANNY: Fuck!
KEVIN: Wait. Everybody,
wait. Just stop.
He's down.
DANNY: Penda, what's the move?
PENDA: Hold it, hold it.
DANNY: What's the play?
PENDA: All right, Roberts,
get in there.
ROBERTS: What?
PENDA: Get in there. Move.
Clear. Clear.
KEVIN:
I got you, I got you.
C over.
PENDA: Ganning, stay back.
Danny, follow me.
Come on, Danny.
Danny, you were there.
PENDA: We saw him.
We told him to stop.DANNY: Yeah.
[BOY GROANING]
DANNY: Fuck. He's a kid.
PENDA: Hey, we told him
to stop.
He didn't even
turn around.
[BOY GROANING]
[BOY SCREAMING]
PENDA: What's in there?
[BOY GROANING]
PENDA: What the fuck? Shit.
He's deaf.
DANNY: What?
The kid's deaf.
That's why he didn't respond to us.
He can't fucking hear.
Oh, fuck me.
Who saw this?
Hey, did anyone
see this?
Ganning, come here.
KEVIN: Okay.
PENDA: All right,
you with me?
Take a look at him.
DANNY: Oh, shit, his teeth.
[BOY GROANING]
DANNY: Oh, shit.
KEVIN: Wait up, here you go.
DANNY: Hey, we really
need to get him a bus.
[BOY SCREAMING]
DANNY: We need to
get him a bus.
PENDA:
He's not gonna make it.
[GASPING]
PENDA: Danny?
Lookit, man.
DANNY: Yeah?
The optics on this
look real bad.
DANNY: Yeah.
You understand me?
DANNY: Uh-huh.
It gets out we shot a kid,
and the public,
and the administration,
and everybody's gonna
ream our ass, okay?
So, I'd appreciate it...
We'd appreciate it
if you cooperate and
let's just keep this
between us.
DANNY:
The kid's bleeding out.
Look at me. Can I
trust you? Danny?
You want a future, right?
DANNY: Yeah.
Can I trust you?
Yeah, you can trust me.
PENDA: Good.
We don't want
any more gunfire.
DANNY: What are you doing?
[BOY SCREAMING]
DANNY: What the fuck
are you doing?
[SCREAMING AND GRUNTING]
PENDA: Easy.[SHUSHES]
[DANNY GROANS]
[SIGHS]
Damn, Danny.
CHRISTOPHER: Mom, you have
such a dangerous job.
You could have picked
so many other ones,
but you picked
to be a police.
Why can't you be a doctor,
or a fireman or something?
Daddy can't even help you.
I wish I could help, though.
No one can.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
KESPER: [ON RECORDING]
This is Kesper.
Leave a message.
RENEE: Sarge,
Danny Holledge is dead.
He was holding evidence.
I'm headed to the old plant
on 53rd and 3rd.
I need to show
you what I have.
[INDISTINCT POLICE RADIO
CHATTER]
Taneesha?
Taneesha, I know
what happened to your son.
RENEE:
Sarge, come upstairs.Renee.
Hey.
What's the evidence
that you have?
Body cam footage of
the night of the murder.
Kind of shit that
starts riots. It's really...
We need to stay unified
about what happened.
Let's talk inside.
Sarge, you saw
that footage, too?
I don't need
to see it.
I just need to
get rid of it.
Letting the public
see the record
would do nothing but
weaken our department.
Holledge kept a copy
of that video?
Where the hell is it?
Danny's dead.
He died because of you.
You know, I always thought
you were a cop first.
I am a cop first, bitch.
[GROANS]
Give me that video, Renee.
[PANTING]
Or the next one goes
in your head
instead of your vest.
[RENEE GROANING]
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
KESPER: What is it?
You killed my son.
Who the fuck are you?
DeMarco.
PENDA: What?
You remember him?
'Cause he remembers you.
[GROANING]
KESPER: Enough of this shit.
[GASPS]
What the fuck is that?
Did you see that?
Behind you.
What?
[GROANING]
Kesper. Kesper!
Help me.
What the fuck?
[GROANING]
[GRUNTS]
RENEE: Come on.
KESPER: Please, help.
[GROANING]
[KESPER GROANING]
You need to leave.
It's DeMarco.
Can't control him.
You need to leave.
No.
No, no, no. Listen,
this ends here.
Let me handle this
the right way.
[METAL CLANGING]
[GRUNTS]
Stay here.
Okay. Okay.
PENDA: Look, Renee.
I just wanna get out of here.
[INDISTINCT WHOOSHING]
Fuck.
[WHIMPERING]
[YELLING]
Drop it, Penda.
[GROANING]
Or the next one's
in your head.
[PANTING]
[PENDA GRUNTING]
[GROANING]
[BONES CRACKING]
[SCREAMING]
[CHOKING]
[VOICE SHUSHING]
[MUFFLED BREATHING]
Don't worry. He knows
you're with me now.
[INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
NEWS ANCHOR: In the end to a stunning trial that riveted the public
and amounted to revelations
of deep-seated corruption
in the Swinton Police
Department,
a jury handed down
their verdict of guilty
to Sergeant Kesper
for the crime of conspiracy
in the murder
of DeMarco Branz.
The trial began
after a video recorded
on the body cam of the late
Officer Daniel Holledge
came to light,
revealing involvement of fellow officers Kevin Ganning,
Gabe Roberts and Dario Penda.
In brief comments
after the trial,
Officer Renee Lomito said
she was just doing her duty.
[MUSIC CONTINUES]